CURRICULUM VITAE

Name : Sai Madhav Kaza Occupation : Software Engineer

Company : Neemus Software Solutions Private Limited

Address : Hanumakonda, Warangal

Telangana - 506011

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am confident and aim about Practical Approaches to solve complex problems. I have expertise more than 2 years of Industrial Experience in Java/J2EE Web Development and C++ Application Development. I am more into Core Development Level of Software Building, Deploying, Testing and Delivery to End-Clients. More than Appraises from Project Clients, I have satisfactorily delivered Complex Applications by going an extra-mile than What Anyone can imagine. I have strong fundamentals of Science/Logical/Mathematic Computation, which keeps me driving in daily life and helps me strengthen skillset.

EDUCATION

• Masters in Computer Science (Spec. Website Development)

Jan. 2020 – Aug. 2021

Central Michigan University

Michigan (USA)

GPA: 3.93/4.0

• Bachelors in Electronics Communication (Spec. Computers)

Aug. 2014 – May 2018

BITS Pilani

Hyderabad (INDIA)

GPA: 7.71/10.0

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

% Neemus Software Solutions Private Limited

Aug. 2023 - Present

Software Engineer

Hyderabad, TG (INDIA)

Project #1 – EMPLTS (ADA, DRDO – Bangalore)

Description: Project comprises of Flight Database to calculate Life of Parts through parameters related to Flight vs Engine Consumption. The Scope consists of dashboard creation for the Life and update it into database as soon as real-time Aircrafts fly and upload the data through third party tools via Application built in C++ Standalone Mode.

Roles and Responsibilities -

- Designed and Developed Core Module of Additional Feature where Data is Exported/ Imported to and fro from the Database.
- Upgraded Backup Java-based Servlet Architecture web-application from Java 6 to Java 8 compatible with Oracle License issued for the Client.
- Tested and Managed SDLC via waterfall and Agile Methodologies for satisfactory delivery at the Onsite Client Location.

Technical Skills: Java/JSP, C++ (QT Framework), Oracle Database, MVC Patterns, TDD (Test Cases)

Project #2 – RMAT (LRDE, DRDO – Bangalore)

Description: Project comprises of Radar Integration with Test System Built-In with parameters and Graphical Representation of Data through Communication/Handshakes between sub-systems. The Scope Consists of subsystem building with Communication (UDP) in the Local Area Network and Full Display GUI with Qt C++ Standalone Mode and Independent Application with all the dependencies in a package.

Roles and Responsibilities -

- Developed Four Modules of RST Application and QCustomPlot Graphical Representation of Data outperforms by usage of Multi-threaded standalone mode of the App.
- UDP based Communication protocol is followed for ACK based Handshaking implemented for Radio Detection and Ranging Technology (Tx/Rx) in the SQLite Database.
- Tested and Managed SDLC through Agile Methodologies for satisfactory delivery at the Onsite Client Location.

Technical Skills: C++ (QT Framework), SQLite Database, MVC/ OOD Pattern

嗡 DRDL Kanchanbagh (DRDO Laboratory)

Aug. 2022 – Aug. 2023

Computer Engineer Hyderabad, TG (INDIA)

Duties and Responsibilities -

- Worked in Project IMIS (Integrated Manufacturing and Information System) under Head of PDD/DOE of DRDL (DRDO Laboratory).
- Maintained Oracle Database Server for all time Availability and debugged issues like Regular Backups, Restore and Oracle Forms Updates according to Technology Director.
- Assisted Team Member for Development of ASP.Net Based web application for Internal DOE Website.

Technical Skills: Java/JSP, Oracle Database, Web Frameworks (HTML, CSS, JS), PL/SQL.

% Strategic Solutions Group LLC

Oct. 2021 – Jan. 2022

Junior Software Engineer Boston, MA (USA)

Duties and Responsibilities –

- Worked in Project MAVEN under EDSS Team comprises of Disease workflows/ Record management for the Massachusetts Government of USA
- Developed workflow-based Servlet Architecture application for maintaining Diseases and Patients records for Massachusetts Government of USA to look at it.
- Followed Agile Methodology in completing Sprint based JIRA tickets within stipulated time.
- Familiarized with AWS Workspace for CloudWatch triggers for Database Related issues at Real-time Production support tasks.

Technical Skills: Java/JSP, Oracle Database, AWS Cloud Watch, Production Support (Bi-Weekly Shifts), Servlets/ Struts.

PART TIME WORK

Central Michigan University

Graduate Assistant

Michigan (USA)

Duties and Responsibilities –

• Managed Doubt-Solving Sessions for Bachelors Students and assisted Mr. Kelly Dylan and Mrs. Li Ling Li in both Teaching of Java Course and Grading to Students.

Technical Skills: Java, Object Oriented Programming Concepts, Grader

% Analog Devices India

Jul. 2017 - Dec. 2018

Design and Verification Intern Bangalore, KA (INDIA)

Duties and Responsibilities -

- Verified the Firmware application built for BLAST Device and Designed the Better Script for Automation with Python.
- Increased Baud Rate, Throughput via process of Connection of Hardware and Performance to OTOSense Cloud with End-to-End application for User Satisfaction in UK, London Client.
- Part of AES Sensors Team, Received Appraises for work performed. Developed Inter-personal Communication as foundation for Practice School II.

Technical Skills: RTOS, Hardware, DSP Processor, Python Scripts, Audio/Video Processing Devices, OTOSense Cloud, Communication Skills.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Achieved 50% Fee Waiver Graduate Assistant Scholarship at CMU (USA) from Aug. 2020 to May 2021.
- Attained 40% Merit Cum Need Scholarship at BITS Pilani (INDIA) from Aug. 2014 to May 2018.
- Awarded Prime Minister Scholarship Scheme for excelling in Post-secondary Education as well as Childs of Ex-servicemen.
- Awardee of INSPIRE Scholarship for scoring top 1% in BIEAP examination in March 2014.
- Scored AIR 6358 (JEE Adv.), AIR 179 (JEE Main B. Arch), AIR 4005 (JEE Main B. Tech) for All over India Exam.
- Scored State Rank 337 (EAMCET) and 327/450 Marks (BITSAT).
- BOSM'16 Silver Medalist in Sports (Carrom).

Aug. 2020 – May 2021